Ross Santee papers, 1926-1977
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Ross Santee papers, 1926-1977
AZ 423
Santee, Ross, 1889-1965
Correspondence with Ray Carlson, editor of Arizona Highways, biographical material, reviews and criticisms, publisher's catalogs and magazine articles which he authored or illustrated.
.4 ft.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Arizona author, artist and cowboy.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence with Ray Carlson, editor of Arizona Highways, biographical material, reviews and criticisms, publisher's catalogs and magazine articles which he authored or illustrated.
Access Terms
Santee, Ross, 1889-1965
Carlson, Raymond, 1906-1983
Correspondence
Clippings
Container List
- Correspondence. Includes dated and undated letters to Raymond Carlson (R.C. or Ray). Some letters illustrated - pen and ink or water color. 1948-1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Biographical materials about Ross Santee appearing in booksellers catalogs, biographical dictionaries and articles apearing in magazines and newspapers. 1938-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Reviews, critiques and checklists of Santee's books. 1935-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bookseller's and publisher's catalogs selling books by Santee. Also include dust jackets advertising two of his books and an Arizona Highways Christmas greeting which he illustrated. 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Magazine articles by Ross Santee. 1928-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Magazine articles illustrated by Ross Santee and exhibition catalogs which include his art works. 1926-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letter addressed "Dear San," dated Monday Jan. 9 (handwritten in ink on white writing paper memo size). (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Retells of the signing and illustrating of a book by Ross (presumably the copy of Dog Days included in the gift) and how to contact Ross through his publisher.
- Letter addressed "Dear Cousin Mary," from Ross (handwritten in ink on white writing paper letter size, illustrated). (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Ross is happy to hear of Mary and her family, recognizing them as part of the greater Santee clan.
- Letter addressed "Dear San," dated 22 March 1948, from Mom (typed on white writing paper letter size, with felt tip pen corrections) with abbreviated family tree diagrammed with notes, in lt. blue ink on card stock. March 22, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Letter includes account of mother's investigations into Santee family geneology and assorted family news.
- Letter in envelope addressed to "Jim and Mary Harris," from Nancy and Gordon Graham, dated 5 January 1995 (typed on copy paper). January 5, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  In reply to an earlier question, the Grahams suggest contacting the UA for information on what to do with Ross Santee manuscripts and sketches.
- Envelope addressed to "Miss Mary C. Santee," from Ross Santee postmarked 8 March 1948, containing a letter from Ross to Mary dated 6 March 1948 (typed white letter paper) and notes by Mary for letters to Ross (handwritten in pencil on green college ruled three ring binder paper). March 6-8, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Letter from Ross relates some of his family history. Mary's notes are for a letter to Ross preceding the above, and a letter thanking him for the above.
- Envelope addressed to "Mary Santee," from Mrs. Ross Santee postmarked 11 January 1949, containing a letter from Eve Santee (typed on letter paper) and a color illustrated letter from Ross (hanwritten in ink on letter paper). January 11, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Both letters invite Mary to visit and a promise to visit.
- Envelope addressed to "Mary C. Santee," from E. Santee post marked 4 January 1950, containing a letter from Eve (typed on letter paper). January 4, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Eve thanks Mary for a letter and tells of Christmas events.
- Red and gold Christmas card to "Mary," from Dad. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Undated letter written in black ink addressed to "Jo" from Ross Santee featuring a sketch of a cowboy campsite. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Undated letter written in black ink addressed to "Jo" from Ross Santee featuring a sketch of a mountain range. (Box 1, Folder 7)